# Joe Malatesta

#### **SUMMARY**

Highly motivated and dedicated Instructional Associate with 2 years of experience at General Assembly. Skilled in classroom support, technical troubleshooting, student engagement, and curriculum development. Committed to enhancing the learning experience and contributing to student success.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### General Assembly - Software Engineering Instructional Associate Online, Remote • 09/2020 - Current

- Collaborated with instructors to enhance classroom engagement and learning outcomes
- Assisted in technical setup and troubleshooting for smooth class delivery
- Provided constructive feedback on student assignments and projects
- · Managed administrative tasks, attendance tracking, and student records
- · Fostered a positive and inclusive learning environment
- · Contributed to curriculum development
- · Analyzed solutions and coding fixes for software problems.
- Developed web applications using variety of engineering languages.

### LevelGreen Landscaping - Heavy Equipment Mechanic Upper Marlboro, MD • 12/2019 - 03/2020

- Diagnosed and repaired mechanical equipment, including hydraulic, diesel, and electric cutting tools
- Conducted DOT inspections on fleet vehicles
- · Maintained and repaired water transfer equipment
- Trained employees on equipment usage and maintenance.

### Community Bridge Inc - SHOP MANAGER Brandywine, MD • 01/2019 - 12/2019

- Diagnosed and repaired mechanical equipment, including hydraulic, diesel, and electric cutting tools
- Managed parts inventory and warehouse
- Trained employees on equipment repairs and best practices.

## Penhall Construction - SMALL ENGINE MECHANIC Upper Marlboro, MD • 10/2016 - 12/2018

- · Diagnosed and repaired hydraulic, diesel, and electric concrete cutting equipment
- Maintained water transfer equipment
- Inspected diamond cutting blades
- Conducted in-shop and field troubleshooting and repairs.

#### CONTACT

joemalatesta@msn.com Dunkirk, MD 20754

#### **SKILLS**

- JavaScript
- React
- Python
- MongoDB
- Mongoose
- HTML/CSS
- Express
- Best Practices
- Code Development
- Complex Problem Solving
- Best Practices and Standards
- Web Technologies
- · Testing and Troubleshooting
- Front-End Development
- MySQL

### EDUCATION AND TRAININ G

Software Engineering: Certificate of Completion of full-time software en ImmersiveGeneral Assembly Dunkirk, MD • 12/2020

General and Culinary Studies Courses Baltimore International College Baltimore, MD • 01/1998

General Studies Courses Anne Arundel Community College Arnold, MD • 01/1995